《玩具总动员3》
Money, money, money. Hey!
钱,钱,钱
You got a date with justice, one-Eyed Bart.
今天你和正义有个约会,独眼巴特
Too bad, Sheriff. I 'm a married man.
真糟糕,警长,我已经结婚了
One-Eyed Betty!
独眼贝蒂
I think you dropped something, mister.
先生,你的东西掉了
- Jessie? - Give it up, Bart!
- 洁西 - 束手就擒吧
You've reached the end of the line!
你的犯罪生涯到头了
I always wanted to go out with a bang!
我总想和爆炸来场约会
- Oh, no! - The orphans!
- 不 - 孩子们
Hate to leave early, but our ride is here.
真不想提前离场,可我们的车来了
It's me or the kiddies, Sheriff. Take your pick.
是追我还是救这些孩子呢,警长,选一个吧
Ride like the wind, Bullseye!
再快一点,红心
Hold him steady!
稳住
Woody, hurry!
伍迪,快点儿
No!
不
Glad I could catch the train!
真高兴我赶上火车了
Now let's catch some criminals.
该去抓罪犯了
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇宙,浩瀚无垠
Reach for the sky.
一飞冲天
You can't touch me, Sheriff!
你抓不住我的,警长
I brought my attack dog with a built-in force field.
我的警卫狗有自带力场
Well, I brought my dinosaur who eats force-field dogs.
我的恐龙专吃力场狗
Evil Dr. Pork Chop!
邪恶博士猪排
That's Mr. Evil Dr. Pork Chop to you.
要称呼我邪恶博士猪排先生
(金刚猴阵)
"Buzz, shoot your laser at my badge."
巴斯,用你的激光枪射我的胸章
"Woody, no. It'll kill you." "Just do it!"
不,伍迪,那会杀了你的,来吧
"You're going to jail, Bart." "Watch out!"
你要进监狱了,巴特,小心
Mom!
妈妈
No, no, no. Just keep playing. Just pretend I 'm not here.
没事儿,继续玩吧,就当我不在
Oh, no, Molly!
不,茉莉
No, it's okay, Mom. It's a 50-foot baby from outer space.
没事,妈妈,来自外太空的50英尺巨婴
And she's on a rampage. Run for your lives!
她会摧毁一切,快逃啊
Buster, get out of there. Does the red light mean it's going?
巴斯特,出来,红灯是在录像吧
Come on. Say "Happy birthday" to Molly.
来吧,和茉莉说生日快乐
- Happy birthday! - Charming.
- 生日快乐 - 真乖
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
- Look how tall you're getting. - Yeah!
- 你都长这么高了 - 是呀
"I came as fast as I could. Buzz, behind you!"
我已经尽快赶来了,巴斯,注意后面
"Got it, Woody."
知道了,伍迪
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
巴斯光年前来救援
"Good work, Buzz."
干的好,巴斯
Okay, places, everyone. Come on, come on. Get in position.
好了,快点,所有人各就各位
Wait! I can't find my other eye.
等等,我的那只眼睛不见了
- All right, whose foot's in my face? - It's mine. Give it back.
- 谁的脚在我脸上 - 是我的,还给我
You have saved our lives. We are eternally grateful.
你救了我们,感激不尽
Buzz! Mind if I squeeze in next to ya?
巴斯,不介意我挤在你旁边吧
Yes. No. I mean, why would I mind squeezing next to you?
介意,不,我为什么要介意我挤在你旁边
Is it hot in here?
这儿太热了
Here they come!
他们来了
Sarge, you got it?
队长,你们拿到了吗
Mission accomplished.
任务完成
Hooray!
万岁
Careful. Careful!
小心,小心
All right, guys. We got one shot at this. Everyone ready?
兄弟们,我们要抓住这次机会,大家准备好了吗
We're ready, Woody. Let's do it!
准备好了,伍迪,行动
Okay, Buzz. Make the call.
好的,巴斯,打电话
Target is on approach.
目标正在接近
Just like we rehearsed it, guys.
就像我们演习的那样
Hello?
你好
Hello? Anyone there?
你好,有人吗
Molly, stay out of my room!
茉莉,别进我房间
I wasn't in your room.
我没有
Then who was messing with my stuff?
那是谁动了我的东西
It wasn't me.
不是我
Well, that went well.
还真是顺利
He held me! He actually held me!
他拿起我了,他真的拿起我了
This is just sad.
太悲剧了
Who we kiddin'? The kid 's 17 years old.
骗谁呢,他已经17岁了
We ain't ever gettin' played with.
他再也不会和我们一起玩了
Guys, hey, hold up.
伙计们,等等
We need a staff meeting. Everyone! A staff meeting!
我们要开个会,所有的玩具都要参加
Not again!
又开会
Come on. Slink, gather everyone up.
别这样,弹簧狗,叫大家开会
We are gathered, Woody.
伍迪,我们都在这
Okay. First of all,
好了,首先,
we all knew operation Playtime was a long shot.
我们都知道"游戏演习"是一次大胆的尝试
More like a misfire.
更像一次失败的行动
But we've always said this job isn't about getting played with. It's about...
可我们常说我们的工作不是被玩,而是为了
Being there for Andy. We know.
为了陪着安迪,我们知道
But we can try again! Right?
我们还以再试一次,对吧
I 'm callin' it, guys. We're closing up shop.
听我说,伙计们,我们收工了
What?
什么
Andy's going to college any day now. That was our last shot.
安迪马上就要上大学了,那是我们最后的机会
We're going into attic mode, folks.
我们马上就要进阁楼了
Keep your accessories with you at all times.
随时拿好你们的零件
Spare parts, batteries, anything you need for an orderly transition.
备件,电池,任何合理过渡期需要的东西
Orderly? Don't you get it? We're done! Finished! Over the hill!
合理过渡,你还不明白吗,我们完了,一切都结束了
Hey, hey, hey, now. Come on, guys. We all knew this day was coming.
别这样,伙计们,我们都知道这一天迟早会来
Yeah, but now it's here.
是啊,现在不就是吗
Look, every toy goes through this. No one wants to see...
听着,每个玩具都有这一天,没人想看到
Hey, Sarge! What are you doing?
队长,你们在干吗
War's over, folks. Me and the boys are moving on.
战争结束了,我们要去其他地方继续战斗
- Moving on? - You're going AWOL?
- 其他地方 - 你是要擅离职守吗
We done our duty. Andy's grown up.
我们完成了任务,安迪长大了
And let's face it, when the trash bags come out,
面对现实吧,如果垃圾袋拿来了
we army guys are the first to go.
那我们肯定是第一个进去的
- Trash bags? - Who said anything about trash bags?
- 垃圾袋 - 谁说垃圾袋了
It has been an honor serving with you. Good luck, folks.
很荣幸能和你们并肩作战,祝你们好运
You're gonna need it.
你们也会有这么一天的
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait, wait!
不,等等
- We're getting thrown away? - No. No one's getting thrown away.
- 我们要被丢掉了吗 - 不,没人会被丢掉
How do you know?
你怎么知道
- We're being abandoned! - We'll be fine, Jessie.
- 我们要被抛弃了 - 我们会没事的,洁西
- So why did Sarge leave? - Should we leave?
- 那队长为什么要离开 - 我们要离开吗
- I thought we were goin' to the attic. - I hate all this uncertainty!
- 我还以为我们要去阁楼呢 - 我讨厌这种不安的感觉
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on now. Wait a minute. Quiet!
等一等,安静
No one's getting thrown out, okay? We're all still here.
没有人会被丢掉,好吗,我们都还在这
I mean, yeah, we've lost friends along the way.
一路走来,我们是失去过朋友
- Wheezy and Etch and... - Bo Peep?
- 企鹅威兹,画板,还有 - 牧羊女
Yeah. Even Bo.
对,还有她
All good toys who've gone on to new owners.
所有的好玩具都有新主人了
But through every yard sale, every spring cleaning, Andy held on to us!
可是每一次的后院拍卖会和大扫除,安迪都留下了我们
He must care about us, or we wouldn't be here.
他肯定很在乎我们,不然我们就不会在这了
You wait. Andy's gonna tuck us in the attic. It'll be safe and warm...
你等着看,安迪会让我们呆在阁楼里,那儿安全又舒服
- And we'll all be together. - Exactly!
- 我们会一直在一起 - 没错
There's games up there, and books, and...
那有游戏,有书,还有,
- The racecar track! - The racecar track. Thank you!
- 赛车跑道 - 赛车跑道,谢谢
- And the old TV. - There you go, the old TV.
- 还有旧电视 - 没错,旧电视
And those guys from the Christmas decorations box. They're fun, right?
还有作圣诞装饰的那些伙计,他们很有意思的
Yeah.
是的
And someday, if we're lucky, Andy may have kids of his own.
也许有一天,如果运气好的话,安迪会有他自己的孩子
And he'll play with us then, right?
他就又能和我们一起玩了
We'll always be there for him.
我们会一直在那等他
Come on, guys. Let's get our parts together, get ready,
来吧,伙计们,把自己的零件都带好
and go out on a high note.
准备迎接新的旅程
I 'd better find my other eye.
最好能找到我的另一只眼睛
Where'd you leave it this time?
这次你把它丢哪了
Someplace dark. And dusty.
一个又黑又脏的地方
Come on. Let's see how much we're going for on eBay.
来吧,看看我们在网上值多少钱
Don't worry. Andy's gonna take care of us. I guarantee it!
别担心,安迪会照顾好我们的,我保证
You guarantee it, huh?
你保证吗
I don't know, Buzz. What else could I say?
我不知道,巴斯,我还能说什么呢
Well, whatever happens, at least we'll all be together.
不管发生什么,最起码我们都会在一起
For infinity and beyond.
飞向宇宙,浩瀚无垠
- Can I have your stereo? - No.
- 能把你的音响给我吗 - 不行
- Why not? - 'Cause I 'm taking it with me.
- 为什么不行 - 我要带走
- Can I have your computer? - No.
- 能把你的电脑给我吗 - 不行
- Your video games? - Forget it, Molly.
- 你的游戏机呢 - 想都别想,茉莉
Okay. Andy, let's get to work here.
好吧,安迪,我们开始干活吧
Anything you're not taking to college either goes in the attic, or it's trash.
所有你不会带去上大学的,要么放进阁楼,要么丢掉
- Mom, I 'm not leaving till Friday. - Come on. It's garbage day.
- 妈妈,我星期五才走呢 - 来吧,今天就开始整理
- Mom. - Look, it's simple.
- 妈妈 - 你瞧,很简单
Skateboard, college. Little League trophy, probably attic.
滑板,带去大学,小联盟奖杯,也许送上阁楼
Apple core, trash. You can do the rest.
苹果核,丢掉,剩下的你来收拾
Why do you still have these toys?
你怎么还留着这些玩具
Molly, out of my room!
茉莉,出去
Three more days and it's mine!
三天后就是我的房间了
Molly, you're not off the hook either.
茉莉,你也有事要做
You have more toys than you know what to do with.
你的玩具太多了
Some of them could make other kids really happy.
你可以送走一些给其他孩子
What kids?
哪些孩子
The children at the daycare. They're always asking for donations.
幼儿园的孩子,他们一直需要捐赠
What's daycare?
什么是幼儿园
- Mom. - No buts.
- 妈妈 - 没有可是
You choose the toys you want to donate, I 'll drop them off at Sunnyside.
你把要捐的玩具挑出来,我顺路带给他们
Poor Barbie.
可怜的芭比
I get the Corvette.
我要巡洋舰
Andy, come on. You need to start making decisions.
安迪,快点,你要做决定了
Like what?
比如什么
Like what are you gonna do with these toys?
比如你要把这些玩具怎么办呢
Should we donate them to Sunnyside?
要不要把它们也捐出去呢
- No. - Maybe sell them online?
- 不 - 或者放在网上拍卖
Mom, no one's gonna want those old toys.
妈妈,没人想要这些旧玩具
They're junk.
都只是废品
Fine. You have till Friday.
好吧,你能留到星期五
Anything that's not packed for college or in the attic
所有不带去大学或送进阁楼的东西
- is getting thrown out. - Whatever you say, Mom.
- 都会被丢掉 - 随你心意,妈妈
- What's happening? - We're getting thrown out, you idiot.
- 怎么了 - 我们要被丢掉了,白痴
That's what's happening.
还问怎么了
- You need a hand? - I got it.
- 要帮忙吗 - 我自己能行
Here.
过来
So, you gonna miss me when I 'm gone?
我走了你会想我吗
- If I say no, do I still get your room? - Nope.
- 如果我说不,我还能住你的房间吗 - 不行
Then, yes, I 'll miss you.
那好吧,我想你
I can't breathe!
我喘不上来气了
- This can't be happening! - Quiet! What's that sound?
- 真不敢相信 - 安静,什么声音
Andy!
安迪
That's not trash. That's not trash!
那些不是垃圾,那些不是垃圾
Think, think, Woody. Think, think, think.
想想办法,伍迪,快想想办法
Buster! Come here, boy! Come here!
巴斯特,过来,过来
Okay, boy. To the curb!
好了,小伙子,到街上去
No, Buster! No!
不,巴斯特,不
Get up. Buster!
起来,巴斯特
- We're on the curb! - I knew it would come to this!
- 我们在街上 - 我就知道是这样
Pull, everyone! Pull!
伙计们,使劲拉啊
- It won't rip! - Forget it!
- 扯不破 - 算了
It's triple- ply, high- density polyethylene!
天哪,这是三层高密度聚乙烯
There's gotta be a way out!
总能找到办法的
Andy doesn't want us. What's the point?
安迪不要我们了,有什么意义?
Point. Point. Point!
尖端,尖头
Push! Push!
推,快推
I can hear the garbage truck!
我听见了垃圾车的声音
It's getting closer.
越来越近了
Buzz! Jessie!
巴斯,洁西
- Andy threw us out. - Like we were garbage.
- 安迪不要我们了 - 就像扔垃圾一样
- Junk. He called us junk. - How could he?
- 废品,他叫我们废品 - 他怎么能这样
This doesn't make any sense.
这没道理
I should have seen this coming. It's Emily all over again.
我早该知道,又是这样
- Sarge was right. - Yeah, and Woody was wrong.
- 队长是对的 - 没错,伍迪错了
Wait a minute. Wait, hold on. This is no time to be hysterical.
等一等,没时间歇斯底里了
It's the perfect time to be hysterical.
现在正是歇斯底里的好时候
- Should we be hysterical? - No!
- 我们应该歇斯底里吗 - 不
- Yes! - Maybe! But not right now!
- 好吧 - 可现在不是时候
Fellas, I know what to do.
伙计们,有办法了
What the heck?
怎么回事
- We should 've done this years ago. - Jessie, wait. What about Woody?
- 几年前我们就该这么做了 - 等等,洁西,伍迪怎么办
He's fine, Buzz. Andy's taking him to college.
他没事,巴斯,安迪会带他去大学的
Now we need to go!
现在我们得走了
You're right. Come on.
你是对的,来吧
- Buzz? - Woody!
- 巴斯 - 伍迪
What's going on? Don't you know this box is being donated?
怎么回事,你们不知道这盒子是要捐给幼儿园的吗
It's under control, Woody. We have a plan.
伍迪,一切尽在掌握,我们有个计划
We're going to daycare!
我们要去幼儿园
Daycare? What, have you all lost your marbles?
幼儿园,什么,你们都疯了吗
Well, didn't you see? Andy threw us away.
你没看见吗,安迪把我们扔了
No, no, no, no. He was putting you in the attic.
不,不是,他要把你们放进阁楼的
Attic? So how did we end up on the curb?
阁楼,那我们怎么会在街上呢
That was a mistake. Andy's mom thought you were trash.
那只是个误会,安迪的妈妈以为你们是垃圾
Yeah. After he put us in a trash bag.
没错,是安迪把我们放进了垃圾袋
And called us junk!
他还叫我们废品
Yeah, I know. It looks bad. But, guys, you gotta believe me.
我知道看起来很糟,可是伙计们,你们一定要相信我
Sure thing, college boy!
当然,大学生
Andy's moving on, Woody. It's time we did the same.
安迪有自己的生活了,伍迪,我们也一样
Okay. Out of the box. Everyone, right now!
离开这个盒子,所有人,马上
Come on, Buzz. Give me a hand. We gotta get this thing outta here.
来吧,巴斯,帮帮忙,我们离开这儿
Woody, wait. We need to figure out what's best for everyone.
伍迪,等一下,我们要弄清楚怎么样对大家最好
Great. Great! It's gonna take us forever to get back here.
好极了,我们再也回不来了
It's all right, Barbie. You'll be okay.
没事的,芭比,你会没事的
Well, Molly and I have been growing apart for years.
茉莉不和我玩很多年了
It's just... I can't believe she would throw me away!
但我还是不敢相信她把我丢掉了
- Welcome to the club, toots. - Okay, everyone, listen up.
- 大家都一样 - 好吧,所有人听着
We can get back to Andy's, but we gotta move fast.
我们还能回到安迪身边,不过我们得动作快点
We'll hide under the seats till we get back home.
在到家之前我们要藏在座位下面
Get it through your vinyl noggin, Woody.
伍迪,别浪费精力了
Andy doesn't want us anymore.
安迪不要我们了
He was putting you in the attic!
他要把你们放进阁楼
He left us on the curb!
他把我们留在了街上
- All right, calm down! Both of you! - Okay, fine. Fine.
- 好了,你们都冷静一下 - 好了
Just wait till you see what daycare's like.
那就去看看幼儿园什么样吧
- Why? What's it like? - Daycare is a sad, lonely place
- 怎么了,那儿什么样啊 - 幼儿园是悲伤和寂寞的地方
for washed- up old toys who have no owners.
充满了没有主人的旧玩具
- Quite the charmer, aren't ya? - You'll see.
- 你还真会安慰人 - 等着瞧吧
As soon as we get to daycare, you'll be begging to go home.
到那儿你们就知道了,到时候你们会哭着要回家
(阳光幼儿园)
Can anyone see anything?
你们能看见什么吗
- There's a playground! - Wow!
- 有游乐场 - 哇！
We hit the jackpot, Bullseye!
我们走运了,红心
So much for sad and lonely, huh?
还真是悲伤和寂寞啊
Okay. Calm down, guys. Let's just keep this in perspective.
冷静,我们要透过现象看本质
Perspective? This place is perfect.
本质,这地方完美
Woody, it's nice! See? The door has a rainbow on it.
伍迪,这儿很不错,看见了吗,门上有彩虹
- Hey there! - Wow!
- 你好 - 哇!
Haven't seen you in ages.
好久不见
I just wanted to drop these old toys off.
我带来了些旧玩具
- Is this Bonnie? - Look how big you are.
- 是邦尼吗 - 都这么大了
- Say hi, sweetie. - Hi.
- 快打招呼,宝贝 - 嗨
Hey, how are your kids? Molly and Andy?
你的孩子怎么样了,茉莉和安迪
Not kids anymore. Andy's going to college on Friday.
不再是孩子了,安迪星期五就要上大学了
- What? - Can you believe it?
- 什么 - 难以置信吧
- You sure they won't miss these? - No, they never get played with.
- 你确定他们不要了吗 - 这些他们都不玩了
- You see any kids? - Where is she taking us?
- 你看到小孩子了吗 - 她要带我们去哪
- Look! - Wow!
- 你瞧 - 哇！
What? What is it?
什么,怎么了
No, no, no.
不
What's the matter with you?
你怎么了
I can't see!
我看不见
Okay, everyone. Recess. Come on!
好了,下课了,快点
- So now what do we do? - We go back to Andy's.
- 我们现在该怎么办 - 我们应该回安迪那
- Anyone see an exit? - Exit, shmexit. Let's get played with.
- 谁看见出口了吗 - 出口,切,我们等着被孩子们玩吧
Careful. These toys might be jealous of new arrivals.
小心,这些玩具会嫉妒新来的玩具
- I want to see! - Hey!
- 我要看一眼 - 嘿
- Rex! - It's my turn!
- 雷克斯 - 到我了
New toys!
新玩具
Well, howdy! Glad to meet ya.
你好,很高兴见到你
Buzz Lightyear at your service.
巴斯光年,为您服务
Boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
天呀
Thank you. May I?
谢谢,我可以吗
The claw!
利爪
Well, hello there. I thought I heard new voices.
欢迎你们,我就觉得听到了新声音
Welcome to Sunnyside, folks. I 'm Lots-o'-Huggin' Bear.
欢迎来到阳光幼儿园,我是抱抱熊罗梭
But please call me Lotso.
但请叫我罗梭
Buzz Lightyear. We come in...
我是巴斯光年,我们,
First thing you gotta know about me, I 'm a hugger.
你首先应该了解的是,我热爱拥抱
Look at you all. You've been through a lot today, haven't ya?
看看你们大家,你们今天一定过得不容易吧
It's been horrible.
非常可怕
Well, you're safe now. We're all castoffs here.
你们现在安全了,这里都是没人要的玩具
We been dumped, donated, yard-saled, secondhanded
被抛弃的,被捐赠的,在后院被拍卖,转手
and just plain thrown out. But just you wait,
或者就直接丢掉了,可是等一等
you'll find being donated was the best thing that ever happened to ya.
你们会发现被捐赠是你们最好的归宿
Mr. Lotso, do toys here get played with every day?
罗梭先生,他们每天都会玩玩具吗
All day long. Five days a week.
一整天,一星期五天
But what happens when the kids grow up?
可如果孩子们长大了呢
Well, now, I 'll tell ya.
我来告诉你
When the kids get old, new ones come in.
等这些孩子们长大了,就会有一批新孩子
When they get old, new ones replace them.
当他们长大了,又有新的孩子代替他们
You'll never be outgrown or neglected, never abandoned or forgotten.
你永远不会被嫌弃,不会被遗弃,或者被忽视
No owners means no heartbreak.
没有主人就不会伤心
- It's a miracle. - And you wanted us to stay at Andy's.
- 真是奇迹 - 你还想让我们回安迪那吗
Because we're Andy's toys!
因为我们是安迪的玩具
So you got donated by this Andy, huh?
你们是被这个安迪捐了是吧
Well, it's his loss, Sheriff. He can't hurt you no more.
这是他的损失,警长,他不能再伤害你了
- Whoa, whoa, no, no, no... - Now, let's get you all settled in.
- 不 - 先把你们安顿一下,肯
Ken? Where is that boy? Ken? New toys!
这家伙哪去了,肯,有新玩具来了
Far out! Down in a jiff, Lotso.
好的,马上下来,罗梭
So, who's ready for Ken's dream tour?
准备好和肯一起开始梦幻之旅了吗
Let's show our new friends where they'll be staying.
带新朋友们去看看他们的新家
Folks, if you want to step right this way...
好了,伙计们,跟我来
Hi, I 'm Ken.
我叫肯
Barbie. Have we ever met?
我是芭比,我们见过吗
I would 've remembered.
见过我会记得的
- Love your legwarmers. - Nice ascot.
- 我喜欢你的长袜 - 好酷的领巾
Come on, Ken. Recess don't last forever.
快点,肯,孩子们要回来了
Right on, Lotso. This way, everybody.
这就开始,罗梭,这边走
You got a lot to look forward to, folks. The little ones love new toys.
今后的日子值得期待,小家伙们总是很喜欢新玩具
- What a nice bear. - And he smells like strawberries.
- 真是好心的熊 - 他闻起来像草莓
Folks, if I can share, here at Sunnyside, we've got,
伙计们,我要告诉大家,这里有
well, just about anything a toy could ask for.
玩具需要的任何东西
Spare parts, superglue,
零件,强力胶
and enough fresh batteries to choke a Hungry Hungry Hippo.
很多的新电池,足以撑死一头饥饿的河马
- Think you're gettin' old? - Wow.
- 你以为自己已经老了 - 哦
Well, stop your worryin'.
不用担心
Our repair spa will keep you stuffed, puffed, and lightly buffed.
我们的休养所会让你立刻返老还童
And this, well, this is where I live.
这是我住的地方
It's Ken's Dream House. It has a disco, it's got a dune buggy.
肯的梦幻小屋,这里有舞厅,越野车
And a whole room just for trying on clothes.
还有一间更衣室
You have everything!
你什么都有
Everything except someone to share it with.
但还需要一位女主人
You need anything at all, you just come talk to me. Here we are.
如果你们需要什么,可以来找我,我们到了
Well, thank you, Big Baby.
谢谢,大宝宝
Why don't you come meet our new friends?
来认识我们的新朋友
Poor baby. We were thrown out together, me and him.
可怜的孩子,我们一起被扔了,我和他
Abandoned by the same owner.
被同一个主人抛弃
But we don't need owners at Sunnyside.
不过在这我们不需要主人
We own ourselves. We're masters of our own fate.
我们是自己的主人,我们自己掌握命运
We control our own destiny.
自己控制我们的未来
Watch out for puddles.
小心水坑
And here's where you folks'll be stayin'.
这就是你们的家了
The Caterpillar Room.
毛毛虫屋
- Look at this place. - Wow!
- 看看这啊 - 哇
Holy moly guacamole.
娘咧
Jackpot, baby.
中奖了,宝贝
- Whoa, puppy! - Hello.
- 可爱的小狗 - 你们好
- Hello. - Hello.
- 你们好 - 你们好
It's so beautiful!
真漂亮
What the... Hey, little guy.
怎么了,小家伙
How long 's it been since you all got played with?
多久没有人找你们玩了
It's been years.
好多年了
Well, just you wait. In a few minutes, that bell's gonna ring,
你只用等几分钟,铃一响
and you'll get the playtime that you've been dreamin' of.
你们梦寐以求的游戏时间就到了
Play! Real play! I can't wait!
游戏,真正的游戏,我都等不及了
Now, if you'll excuse us, we best be headin' back.
请大家原谅,我们要回去了
Welcome to Sunnyside, folks.
欢迎来到阳光幼儿园
- Thank you. - Take care, pinky.
- 谢谢 - 保重,粉嘟嘟
- Goodbye, Mr. Lotso. Thank you. - Thank you, buddy boy.
- 罗梭先生,再见,谢谢你 - 谢谢,伙计
- Will I see you again? - I 'll see you tonight
- 我们还能再见面吗 - 今晚见
- in my dreams. - No.
- 在梦中 - 不
Ken, let's get a move on.
肯,我们该走了
Barbie, come with me. Live in my dream house.
芭比,跟我走吧,住进我的梦幻小屋
I know it's crazy. I know we just met.
我知道这很疯狂,我知道我们才刚刚见面
Heck, you don't know me from G.I. Joe,
你不知道我在《特种部队》里的样子
but when I look at you, I feel like we were...
可每当我看着你,我觉得我们
- Made for each other... - ...made for each other.
- 天生一对 - 天生一对
- Yay! - Yes.
- 太好了 - 是的
- Ken? - Coming, Lotso.
- 肯, - 我来了,罗梭
This is so exciting!
我太激动了
Sounds like kids to me.
听起来像上孩子们
I want to get played with. Why can't time go faster?
我们又能被孩子们玩了,时间怎么不能过的再快一点
How many you reckon are out there?
外面有多少孩子
They sound so sweet.
他们的声音真好听
Look, everyone, it's nice here, I admit.
听着,这不错,我承认
But we need to go home.
可我们要回家
We can have a whole new life here, Woody.
伍迪,我们要在这开始新生活了
A chance to make kids happy again.
又有逗孩子们开心的机会了
- Why don't you stay? - Yeah, Woody. Stay with us.
- 你干吗不留下来 - 是啊,伍迪,留下来吧
- Come on, Woodster! - You'll get played with.
- 拜托,伍迪 - 你又能和孩子们玩了
- I can't. No. - Stay here.
- 我做不到 - 留下吧
- You can make a new kid happy. - No, no. Guys, really. No!
- 你会成为其他孩子的开心果 - 不行,伙计们,真的不行
I have a kid. You have a kid. Andy!
我已经有一个能让其开心的孩子了,你们也有,他就是安迪
And if he wants us at college, or in the attic,
不管他想带我去大学或者放进阁楼里
well, then, our job is to be there for him.
我们的工作就是为了他待在那里
Now, I 'm going home.
现在,我要回家了
Anyone who wants to join me is welcome. Come on, Buzz.
想和我一起走的,我热烈欢迎,走吧,巴斯
Buzz?
巴斯
Our mission with Andy is complete, Woody.
伍迪,陪伴安迪成长的任务已经完成了
What?
什么
And what's important now is we stay together.
现在重要的是我们大家在一起
We wouldn't even be together if it weren't for Andy!
如果不是安迪,我们都不可能在一起
Look under your boot, Buzz. You, too, Jessie.
看看你的靴子,巴斯,还有你,洁西
Whose name is written there?
上面写着谁的名字
Maybe Andy doesn't care about us anymore.
也许安迪不在乎我们了
Of course he does. He cares about all of you!
他当然在乎,他在乎你们大家
He was putting you in the attic. I saw.
他要把你们放进阁楼,我看见了
You can't just turn your back on him now!
你们不能现在背叛他
Woody, wake up! It's over! Andy is all grown up!
伍迪,醒醒吧,都结束了,安迪长大了
Okay, fine. Perfect.
好吧,很好
I can't believe how selfish you all are.
真不敢相信你们这么自私
So this is it? After all we've been through.
缘分尽了是吗,在一起经历了那么多之后
Bullseye, no. You need to stay.
红心,不,你留在这
Bullseye, no, I said, "Stay!"
红心,不,我说了留下
Look,
听着
I don't want you left alone in the attic, okay? Now, stay.
我不想你一个人留在阁楼里,好吗,回去吧
Bonnie?
邦尼
I gotta go.
我得走了
Bonnie, you in here?
邦尼,你在吗
Come on. Come on. Oh, no, no.
很好,很好,不
What... What the heck?
什么,搞什么
Now, that's better.
现在好多了
- Bonnie! - Bluebells, cockleshells...
- 邦尼 - 风信子,海扇壳
There you are. Come on, honey. It's time to go home.
你在这儿,来吧,宝贝,该回家了
No, no, no, no!
不
Reach for the sky!
一飞冲天
Bluebells, cockleshells. Eenie, miny...
风信子,海扇壳,我们大家一起来
You're my favorite deputy.
你是我最信赖的助手
- Bonnie! - Coming!
- 邦尼 - 来啦
Great.
这下好了
It's gonna be okay, Bullseye.
一切都没事的,红心
Woody's going to college with Andy. It's what he's always wanted.
安迪会带上伍迪一起去大学,那正是他想要的
He's crazy. College is no place for a toy.
他疯了,大学里可容不下一个玩具
Toys are for playtime.
玩具是为了玩耍
Speaking of playtime, they're lining up out there!
说到玩耍,孩子们在排队啦
- How many? - There must be dozens.
- 有多少 - 有好多
I can hardly wait!
我等不及了
Places, everyone!
各就各位
At last! I 'm gonna get played with!
终于有人会找我玩了
- Rex? - Come to papa.
- 雷克斯 - 孩子们来吧
there's a snake in my boot.
有只蛇在我的靴子里
I'd like to join your posse, boys, but first I'm gonna sing a little song.
加入你们可以,但我要先唱首歌
A sheriff!
一位警长
Move over, Mr. Pricklepants.
让开,刺猬罗宾先生
We have a guest. You want some coffee?
我们有位客人,来点咖啡
It's good for you. But don't drink too much, or you'll have to...
喝一点对身体有益,但别喝太多,否则
Be right back!
马上回来
Hey, hello? Hi. Excuse me.
你好,请问
Can you tell me where I am?
能告诉我这是哪儿吗
The guy's just asking a question.
那家伙在问你问题
Well, excuse me. I 'm trying to stay in character.
抱歉,我想扮演好角色
My name's Buttercup. You've met Baron von Shush.
我叫巴特,这位是巴伦·范·嘘
Hello, I 'm Trixie.
你好,我是崔西
Guys, hey. Guys, look, I don't know where I am.
大伙听着,我不知身处何方
We're either in a cafe in Paris or a coffee shop in New Jersey.
我们要么在巴黎的咖啡店,要么在新泽西的咖啡屋
I 'm pretty sure I just came back from the doctor
我可以肯定的是,医生告诉我
with life-changing news.
一个惊天的消息
We do a lot of improv here. Just stay loose, have fun, you'll be fine.
我们都是即兴表演,放轻松,好好享受,就没事了
- No, no, no, no. I... - Who wants lunch?
- 不,我 - 谁肚子饿啦
It has a secret ingredient. Jelly beans.
我有秘密配方哦,特制软糖
Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
有人在水塘里投毒
Poison? Who would do such a mean thing?
投毒,这么可恶的事谁干的
The scary witch! Look out! She's using her witch-y powers!
坏女巫,小心,她在施展魔法
"I know where to hide."
我知道藏哪儿
She'll never find us in here.
她别想找到我们
What's wrong?
怎么啦
She found us! We need a spaceship to get away from the witch!
被发现了,我们需要太空船来逃离女巫
- You're doing great! - Are you classically-trained?
- 你真在行 - 你是科班出生的吗
Look, I just need to know how to get out of here!
我只想知道怎么离开这儿
There is no way out.
无路可逃
Just kidding. Door's right over there.
开玩笑,门就在那儿
Well, cowboy, you just jumped right in, didn't ya? I 'm Dolly.
你是新来的吧,我叫多莉
- Woody. - Woody?
- 伍迪 - 伍迪
Really? You're gonna stick with that?
要不考虑换个名字
'Cause now's your chance to change it, new room and all.
这是个机会,在新的家里
That's coming from a doll named Dolly.
例如我是洋宝宝,所以我叫多莉
- Who's the new guy? - Are you a real cowboy?
- 这新来的是谁 - 你真的是牛仔吗
- Well, actually... - 'Course he's not, pea brain.
- 实际上 - 他肯定不是,小豆角
- He don't even have a hat. - I do too have... My hat!
- 他连牛仔帽都没有 - 我当然有,帽子呢
- Told ya. - I found a spaceship!
- 我就说 - 我找到飞船了
Showtime.
好戏开始
Quick, get in. Fasten your seat belts.
快进去,绑好安全带
Close your tray tables. Hold on. It might get a little bumpy.
收好折叠餐桌,坐稳,有点颠簸
Three, two, one, blastoff!
三,二,一,发射
You saved us, cowboy. You're our hero.
你救了我们大伙,你真是英雄
I got a kink in my slink.
我的弹簧打结了
My tail! Where's my tail?
我的尾巴呢
Someone need a hand?
有人少了一只手吗
- Where's my nose? - Here it is.
- 鼻子呢 - 这儿
- Here's your arm. - Give me that. That's mine.
- 给你的胳膊 - 给我,那是我的
Honey, the mustache?
亲爱的,我的胡子
I don't recall playtime being quite that strenuous.
我不记得游戏时间会这么累
Andy never played with us like that.
安迪不会这么对我们
We're just gonna have to make the best of it.
我们尽力了
But these toddlers, they don't know how to play with us.
这些小孩根本就不懂怎么对待玩具
- They're too young! - Yeah, they're sticky.
- 他们太小了 - 他们全身都粘粘的
Well, we should be in the Butterfly Room.
我们应该在蝴蝶屋的
- With the big kids! - That's right.
- 和大一点孩子一起, - 对
- Yeah, you said it. - We'll get this straightened out.
- 没错 - 我们会把事情弄清楚的
I 'll go talk to Lotso about moving us to the other room.
我去和罗梭谈谈,把我们换到蝴蝶屋去
Blast. Try that one.
该死,试试那个
It's locked!
锁上了
- Same here. - Try the windows.
- 这儿也是 - 窗户呢
Negatory. It's a Fenster-Schneckler 380.
不行,这是最先进的电子窗
Finest childproof lock in the world.
防止小孩乱动
- We're trapped! - Wait.
- 我们出不去了 - 等等
Did anyone notice the transom?
有人注意到气窗了吗
Oh, great. How do we get up there?
我们如何爬上去
All right, everyone. On three! One, two...
大伙儿等我数到三,一,二
- Three! - Whoa!
- 三 - 哇
Let go!
去吧
Go!
跳
- He did it! - Yes, sir!
- 他成功了 - 好样的
Way to go, Buzz!
漂亮,巴斯
Yeah, you think they had a fun playtime?
他们以为有好日子过了
They might hear you.
隔墙有耳
- Okay, now you start. - I...
- 你先开始 - 我
- Love... - You.
- 爱 - 你
See? That time, I said "love." Okay, now me first.
刚才我说的"爱"字,现在我先来
- Okay, okay, okay. - I...
- 好 - 我
- Love... - You.
- 爱 - 你
You see what I mean? It changes every time.
明白了吧,每次都会变哦
You are so smart.
你真有才
Come on, Romeo. We're late.
快点,罗密欧,别迟到了
- I 'll wait up for you. - Kisses!
- 我会想你的 - 亲亲
All right, place your bets. Come on, everybody.
快下注吧,各位
- Come on. Any splits? - Heya. Bring it here.
- 有人要退出吗, - 好了,来
- All right. - Here we go.
- 好了 - 开始
- Come on, horsey, come on! - Come on, turkey, come on, turkey.
- 马,马 - 火鸡,火鸡
- Gobble, gobble, baby. - Come on, horsey.
- 火鸡,火鸡 - 马,马
Come on, duck.
鸭子,鸭子
- All right, that's it. No more bets. - Come on! Right here.
- 好了,停止下注 - 停在这里
Let me have the duck, let me have the duck, let me have the duck!
我要鸭子,我要鸭子
Here is a duck.
是鸭子
- I won! - Ah, man!
- 我赢了 - 喔,伙计
- Well, Stretch takes the round. - You lost!
- 章鱼赢了 - 你输了
Okay, minimum bet, five Monopoly.
赌注,最小五片
- Coyote's wild. - Here, here.
- 上不封顶 - 来
- Two greens here. - Changing two double A's.
- 两张绿的 - 新一轮开始
Hey, what do you guys think of the new recruits? Any keepers?
你们觉得新来的玩具们怎样,能作管理员吗
Oh, please! Landfill!
拜托,一堆垃圾吧
- Cowgirl? Dinosaur? - Toddler fodder.
- 女牛仔,恐龙 - 小孩子的玩意
But that space guy, he could be useful.
但那个太空人,他也许有用
He ain't the sharpest knife in the place where they keep the knives.
但他不是最厉害的
Neither are you, Chunk.
你也不是,小胖
You got a little keeper yourself, didn't you, Ken?
肯,你不是给自己留了一个
Hey, lay off, Twitch. Barbie's different.
别管闲事,特维奇,芭比不同
Aw, Mr. Softy over here.
白马小王子
What do you expect from a girl's toy?
你指望女生的玩具能有啥出息
I 'm not a girl's toy! I 'm not! Why do you guys keep saying that?
我不是女生的玩具,我不是,你们干吗老这么说
All them toys are disposable.
那些玩具都不用留着
We'll be lucky if they last us a week.
能坚持一周就不错了
Well, well. Looky who we have here.
瞧瞧这是谁
Let me go!
放开我
Take him to the libary.
带他去图书馆
No!
不
1225 Sycamore.
西迦摩尔大街,1225号
Woody, what are you doing?
伍迪,你在干吗
I gotta get outta here.
我得离开
- You're leaving? - But didn't you have fun today?
- 你要走了 - 难道你今天不开心吗
Well, of course I did, more than I 've had in years,
当然开心,几年中最开心的一天
but, you see, I belong to someone else.
但我属于别人
- Who's "Yid-nuh"? - I believe it's pronounced "Yid-nay".
- 谁是"第岸" - 应该念"堤岸"
Guys, it says "Andy."
伙计们,那是安迪
He's my Bonnie.
他是我的邦尼
And he's leaving soon. I gotta get home.
他马上要走了,我要马上回家
- Where's home? - Elm Street. 234 Elm.
- 你家在哪 - 艾尔姆街,234号
- You guys have a map? - We're on it, cowboy. Trixie?
- 你们有地图吗 - 我们来搞定,崔西
I 'll fire up the computer.
我去开电脑
Unhand me, you cowards! I demand to talk to Lotso!
快松绑,懦夫,我要与罗梭对话
Zip it, Buck Rogers.
闭嘴,太空人
You don't talk to Lotso till we say you can...
没我们的允许别想和罗梭对话
Ken? What's goin' on here? Why is this toy tied up?
肯,怎么回事,干吗绑着他
He got out, Lotso.
他逃出来了,罗梭
"Got out"? No, no, no, no, no. This isn't how we treat our guests.
逃出来,不,怎么能这么对待客人
F-oh, my Schwarz. There you go. I 'm so sorry.
上帝保佑你,好了,抱歉
- Lotso, there's been a mistake. - A mistake?
- 罗梭,我想有些误会 - 误会
The children in the Caterpillar Room are not age-appropriate
毛毛虫屋里的孩子们的年龄
for me and my friends.
并不适合我和我的朋友们
We respectfully request a transfer to the Butterfly Room.
我们真诚地希望能调至蝴蝶屋
Well, request granted!
同意
- But, Lotso... - Hush now, Kenneth.
- 但是,罗梭 - 好了,肯尼斯
This toy's shown initiative, leadership.
这个玩具很上进,是个领袖人物
Why, I 'd say we've found ourselves a keeper.
我觉得,你适合当管理员
Hear that, everyone? We got a keeper!
大伙听到吗,我们有了个新管理员
We're calling you up to the big leagues, son.
加入我们高级领导层吧,孩子
From now on, you'll have anything you want.
现在你想怎样就怎样
Excellent. I 'll go get my friends.
很好,我去接我的朋友们
Whoa, whoa. Hold on there, boss.
等一下,先生
Those Caterpillar kids need someone to play with.
毛毛虫屋的孩子们需要玩具
But my friends don't belong there.
但我的朋友不属于那儿
None of us do, I agree.
大家都一样,你说的对
Which is why, for the good of our community,
但为了这个大家庭
we ask the newer toys, the stronger ones,
新来的,结实的玩具
to take on the hardships the rest of us can't bear anymore.
必须经受那些老一辈经受不起的磨难
Well, I guess that makes sense.
有道理
But I can't accept. We're a family. We stay together.
但我不接受,我们是一家人,不能分开
Family man, huh? I understand.
一家人,我明白了
Put him back in the timeout chair.
把他给我绑回去
What are ya... Unhand me!
放开我
Bring in the Bookworm.
叫书虫过来
Here it is.
找到了
It was filed under "Lightyear."
归档在光年系列下
Let's see here.
我们来看看
"Accessories. Maintenance." Here we go.
零件,维护,找到了
"Remove screws to access battery compartment."
移除螺丝,打开电池仓
What are you doing?
你想干吗
Stop!
住手
Let go of me!
放开我
"To return your Buzz Lightyear action figure to its original factory settings..."
若欲将该巴斯光年太空人恢复至出厂状态
No!
不要
"...slide the switch from Play to Demo".
请将开关从"游戏"切换至"演示"
Stop! No! No! No!
住手,不
- What was that? - Sounds like it came from the hall.
- 什么声音 - 从大厅传来的
I 'll see what it was.
我来看看
What do you see? Anything?
看见什么吗
No, just a dark hallway and... Wait. Wait!
黑漆漆的走廊,等等
I see Andy!
我看见安迪了
- What? - That's impossible.
- 什么 - 这不可能
No, no, I really see him. In his room.
我真的看见他了,在他的房间里
My other eye! The one I left behind.
明白了,我另一只眼睛遗留在他房间里的
this is so weird. He's packing up.
感觉真奇怪,他在打包东西
Here comes Buster. Out of the way! Get away!
巴斯特过来了,让开
Okay, Andy's out in the hall.
好的,安迪在房间外的走廊
He's looking in the attic.
在阁楼里找东西
Wait, there's Mom. Why is he so upset?
等等,母亲来了,他为什么那么生气
Oh, no! Oh, this is terrible!
不,这太糟糕了
He's looking for us. Andy's looking for us!
他在找我们,安迪在找我们
He's looking for us?
他在找我们
So Andy does want us. I knew it! I just knew it!
我就知道,安迪需要我们
I think he did mean to put us in the attic.
我想他确实原本想把我们放进阁楼里的
Well, then, Woody was telling the truth.
看来伍迪说的是真的
- Holy cow! - And you didn't believe him.
- 该死 - 你还怀疑他
Hey, you didn't believe him first!
你先开始怀疑的
Guys, we gotta... We gotta go home!
大伙儿,我们要回家了
- Lotso! - Hey, there.
- 罗梭 - 你们好
How y'all doin' this fine evenin'?
这个宁静的夜晚过得如何
Thank goodness! Have you seen Buzz?
谢天谢地,看见巴斯了吗
There's been a mistake. We have to go.
之前有点误会,我们要走了
Go? Why, you just got here. In the nick of time, too.
走,为什么,你们才来不久
We were runnin' low on volunteers for the little ones.
陪小朋友玩的志愿者不多了
They just love new toys, now, don't they?
他们喜欢新玩具
"Love"? We've been chewed, kicked, drooled on.
喜欢,我们被咬,被踢,被舔
Just look at my pocketbook!
看看我的小包包
Well, here's the thing, sweet potato. You ain't leavin' Sunnyside.
亲爱的土豆,情况是这样,你们不能离开阳光幼儿园
"Sweet potato"! Who do you think you're talking to?
亲爱的土豆,你以为在跟谁说话
I have over 30 accessories, and I deserve more respect...
我有超过30个配件,你给我放尊重点
That's better.
这样更好
Hey, no one takes my wife's mouth, except me.
除了我,谁都不能抢走我太太的嘴
Give it back, you furry air freshener!
还给我,你这公仔熊
Come on, guys. We're goin' home.
来吧大伙,我们回家
Whoa there, missy.
这位女士
You're not goin' anywhere.
你们哪儿也去不了
Oh, yeah? And who's gonna stop us?
谁敢挡道试试看
Buzz! You're back!
巴斯,你来了
Buzz?
巴斯
Hey!
嘿
Look out!
小心
What are you, nuts?
你疯了
Buzz!
巴斯
Prisoners disabled, Commander Lotso!
囚犯已被制服,罗梭长官
- Buzz, what are you doing? - Silence, minions of Zurg!
- 巴斯,你在干吗 - 闭嘴,索戈的走狗
You're in the custody of the Galactic Alliance!
你们被银河联盟拘留了
- "Zurg"? - "Galactic Alliance"?
- 索戈 - 银河联盟
Oh, boy.
天哪
Good work, Lightyear. Now, lock 'em up!
干得好,巴斯,把他们关起来
Yes, sir!
遵命
Where do you think you're going?
你想去哪
Buzz! We're your friends!
巴斯,我们是朋友
Spare me your lies, temptress.
省省力气吧,妖妇
Your emperor's defeated,
你的君主已经被打败
and I 'm immune to your bewitching good looks.
我不会被你妖艳的外表所迷惑
Hey, Mongo! Keep your paws off my wife!
臭鼬,把你的爪子从我老婆身上拿开
Hey! Let go of me, you drooling doofus!
放开我,你这笨蛋
Not him.
等等
I think this potato needs to learn himself some manners.
这颗土豆需要学学礼貌
Take him to the box.
把他关进沙箱里
Hey! Put me down, you moron! Where are you taking me?
放开我,呆子,你要带我去哪
Bad baby! Bad baby!
坏宝宝
Ken? What's going on?
肯,怎么了
Barbie! I told you to wait in the Dream House.
芭比,不是叫你在梦幻小屋等我的
What are you doing to my friends?
你把我的朋友们怎么了
Get in there!
进去
- Barbie, wait! - Don't touch me.
- 芭比,等等 - 别碰我
- We're through! - Barbie! I did...
- 我们完了 - 芭比
And give me my scarf back!
围巾还我
Lightyear! Explain our overnight accommodations.
巴斯,解释一下这里过夜的规则
Sir, yes, sir! Prisoners sleep in their cells.
遵命,囚犯在牢房里就寝
Any prisoner caught outside their cell spends the night in the box.
若被发现不在牢房内,当晚关进沙箱里
Roll call at dusk and dawn.
早晚各点名一次
Any prisoner misses roll call, spends the night in the box.
如果缺席,当晚关进沙箱里
Prisoners do not speak unless spoken to.
只有问你话才能张嘴
Any prisoner talks back, spends the night...
如果敢顶嘴,当晚
In the box! We get it.
关进沙箱里,知道了
At ease, soldier. They're neutralized.
算了,大兵,她没有威胁了
But remember, they'll say anything to make you doubt yourself.
但是记住,他们很有可能使用反间计
Don't worry, Commander.
别担心,长官
Any doubt I had got pounded out of me at the academy.
在银河学院里我已经摒弃了一切杂念
Listen up, folks.
听着,小老百姓
We got a way of doin' things here at Sunnyside.
这儿有这儿的规矩
If you start at the bottom, pay your dues,
从基层开始好好干的话
life here can be a dream come true!
美梦迟早会成真的
But if you break our rules, step outta line,
但如果你们打破规矩胡来
try to check out early, well, you're just hurtin' yourselves.
盘算着提前出狱,那一定是自作自受
Woody! What did you do to him?
伍迪,你对他做了什么
You all get a good night's rest.
晚上好好休息
You got a full day of playtime tomorrow.
明天有的玩呢
1225 Syca...
西迦摩尔大街,1225
Who's Velocistar237?
无敌星237是谁啊
That's just a dinosaur toy down the street.
隔壁街的一只恐龙玩具而已
That's nothing. Let me just take care of that.
没什么,我来应付
- Just a dinosaur. - All right.
- 就是一恐龙 - 好吧
Sycamore. Okay, enter!
西迦摩尔,回车
Please don't be far. Please, please!
千万别太远
Right around the corner? It's right around the corner!
就在拐角处,就在拐角处
I 'm going to college! Look at me! I 'm big toy on campus! Hello!
好好瞧瞧,我在玩具界可是响当当哦
- Hey, I 'll see you at the sock hop. - Okay, Potsie.
- 舞会上见啦 - 好的,帅邮差
Hey, listen. If any of you guys ever get to Sunnyside Daycare,
等下,如果你们去阳光幼儿园的话
you tell 'em Woody made it home.
告诉他们伍迪已经回家了
- You came from Sunnyside? - But how'd you escape?
- 你从阳光幼儿园来的 - 你是怎么逃出来的
Well, it wasn't easy.
不容易
What do you mean "escape"?
你说"逃"什么意思
Sunnyside is a place of ruin and despair.
阳光幼儿园充满了毁灭与绝望
Ruled by an evil bear who smells of strawberries.
由一只草莓味道的邪恶熊掌管着
Lotso?
罗梭
The guy may seem plush and huggable on the outside,
它外表看上去和蔼可亲
but inside, he's a monster.
内心却是一只禽兽
But... How do you know that?
你们怎么知道
Chuckles. He'll tell you.
由小丑来告诉你
Yeah, I knew Lotso.
我认识罗梭
He was a good toy. A friend.
他曾是个好玩具,好朋友
Me and him, we had the same kid, Daisy.
我们的主人是黛西
A was there when Lotso got unwrapped.
我看着主人打开罗梭的包装
Daisy loved us all.
黛西很爱我们
But Lotso,
而且
Lotso was special.
特别爱罗梭
they did everything together.
他们形影不离
You've never seen a kid and a toy more in love.
我从没见过一个孩子如此喜爱他的玩具
One day, we took a drive.
一日我们出去旅游
Hit a rest stop. Had a little playtime.
在休息站,我们小玩了一会
After lunch, Daisy fell asleep.
午餐后,黛西睡着了
She never came back.
她再也没有回来
Lotso wouldn't give up.
罗梭不愿意放弃
It took forever, but we finally made it back to Daisy's.
虽然旅途艰辛,但我们还是回到黛西家
But by then, it was too late.
但一切的一切的都晚了
Something changed that day inside Lotso.
那天,罗梭内心有什么东西变了
Something snapped.
突然之间
She replaced us. Come on!
她买了新玩具替代了我们,我们走
- No, she only replaced you! - She replaced all of us.
- 不,只是你被替代了 - 我们都被替代了
Didn't she?
不是吗
She don't love you no more!
她不再爱你了
Now come on!
我们走
We were lost. Cast off. Unloved. Unwanted.
我们被遗忘,被抛弃,没人爱,没人要
then we found Sunnyside.
随后我们到了阳光幼儿园
But Lotso wasn't my friend anymore.
但罗梭已不再是一个朋友
He wasn't anyone's friend.
谁的朋友也不是
He took over Sunnyside and rigged the whole system.
他掌管了阳光幼儿园,制定了严格的体制
So how'd you get out?
那你怎么逃出来
I got broke. Bonnie found me, took me home.
我坏掉了,邦尼发现了我并带回家
Other toys, they weren't so lucky.
其它的玩具,就没那么幸运
It ain't right what Lotso done. New toys,
罗梭是邪恶的
they don't stand a chance.
新玩具毫无选择的机会
- But my friends are in there. - You can't go back.
- 但我的朋友在里面 - 你不能回去
Returning now would be suicide!
回去就是自杀
But what about your Andy?
还有你的安迪呢
Isn't he leaving for college?
他不是要离家去大学吗
Quiet, musical hog! Knock it off!
别吵,音乐小猪,放下口琴
Oh, Bullseye. I miss Woody, too.
红心,我也想伍迪
But he ain't ever comin' back.
但他不会回来了
(安迪)
Rise and shine, campers!
大家早上好
Commander Lotso, sir!
罗梭长官
All quiet, nothing to report.
一切正常,别无异样
Excellent, Lightyear. Come on. We need ya back at Star Command.
很好,巴斯,上车,我们要回星际指挥部
Wait! What've you done with my husband?
等等,你们把我老公怎么了
Big Baby.
大宝宝
Sweetheart!
亲爱的
It was cold and dark. Nothing but sand and a couple of Lincoln Logs.
那里又黑又冷,只有沙子和一些积木
I don't think those were Lincoln Logs.
我觉得那些不是积木
You all get ready. You got a play-date with destiny!
好好准备一下,好好履行你们的职责
Hello?
你好
You shouldn't have come back, cowboy.
你不该回来的,牛仔
they've cracked down hard since you left. More guards, more patrols.
你离开后,他们受了欺压而且还派更多看守提高巡逻密度
You and your friends ain't ever getting out of here now.
你和你的朋友别想离开这儿
I made it out once.
我逃走过一次
You got lucky once. Want my advice?
那是你幸运,想听我的建议不
Keep your heads down. You'll survive.
低调点,就能活下来
Yeah, for how long?
低调多久啊
I've been here years.
我在这儿好几年了
they'll never break me.
从没坏过
there's only one way toys leave this place.
想离开这儿只有一条路
Poor fella. Trash truck comes at dawn.
可怜的伙计,垃圾车破晓时过来
Then it's off to the dump.
开去垃圾场
Look, I appreciate your concern, old-timer.
谢谢你的关心,老前辈
But we have a kid waiting for us. Now, we're leaving.
我的主人还在等我们呢,我们马上要走
If you'd help us, one toy to another, I 'd sure be grateful.
如果你能帮助我们大家,我会非常感激
Well, if you're gonna get out,
如果你想离开
first thing you gotta get through's the doors.
首先要搞定的是那些门
Locked, every night. Inside and out. Keys are left on a hook in the office.
每晚必锁,从里到外,钥匙挂在办公室的墙上
Got it. What else?
明白,还有什么
Lotso has trucks patrolling all night long.
罗梭的卡车队伍通宵巡逻
Hallway, lobby, playground.
走廊,大厅,操场都有人
Yeah, yeah, yeah. What about the wall?
知道了,怎么穿过围墙
Eight-feet high. Cinder block. No way through it.
8英尺的高墙,无法穿过
You go over or under.
要么翻过去,要么挖地洞
That's it? Doesn't seem so bad.
仅此而已,不算太坏
It's not. Your real problem's the monkey.
错,你真正的问题是猴子
The monkey's the eye in the sky.
猴子眼观六路
He sees everything.
监控着一切
Classrooms.
课室
Hallways.
走廊
Even the playground.
甚至游乐场
You can unlock doors, sneak past guards, climb the wall,
就算有人能撬开门锁,躲过守卫,飞檐走壁
but if you don't take out that monkey, you ain't going nowhere.
可是如果你不先解决掉猴子,你哪都走不了
You wanna get out of here? Get rid of that monkey!
想逃出这里是吗,除掉猴子再说
Recess! Come on, kids!
孩子们,过来,课间休息
Hey, guys.
伙伴们
- Woody? - Woody!
- 是伍迪吗 - 伍迪
Woody!
伍迪
- Hey, hey, hey, buddy! - Thank goodness!
- 伙计 - 谢天谢地
- You're alive! - 'Course I 'm alive!
- 你还活着 - 我当然还活着
Hey, my hat! Wait, where's Buzz?
我的帽子,等等,巴斯呢
Lotso did something to him!
罗梭对他动了点手脚
He thinks he's a real Space Ranger again.
他现在又认为自己是个太空游侠了
- Oh, no. - Oh, yes.
- 不会吧 - 是的
Return of the astro-nut.
宇宙白痴回归
Woody, we were wrong to leave Andy. I was wrong.
伍迪,我们当初不应该离开安迪的,我错了
Jessie's right, Woody. She was wrong.
洁西说得没错,她是错了
No, no, it's my fault for leaving you guys.
不不,我选择离开你们才是真正的错误
From now on, we stick together.
从现在开始,我们永不分离
But Andy's leavin' for college.
但是安迪马上就要去上大学了啊
College? Hog-tie the mailman!
大学,我们得赶快行动
We gotta get you home before Andy leaves tomorrow!
我们要在明天安迪出发之前把你送回家
Tomorrow? But that means...
明天,那意味着
It means we're busting out of here, tonight.
我们得马上逃出去,就今天晚上
- What? Impossible! - But there's no way out of here!
- 什么,不可能的 - 这里根本没有办法可以逃出去
No, there is one way out.
不,有路可逃
One way.
有一条路
Okay, here's what we're gonna do.
我们下面这么办
- Springy dog. - Present.
- 弹簧狗 - 在
Green guys.
绿娃娃
- Cowgirl. - Here.
- 女牛仔, - 在
Horse.
马
- Piggy bank. - Y o.
- 小猪存钱罐 - 在
- Tyrannosaurus. - Here.
- 霸王龙 - 在
- Barbie. - Here.
- 芭比 - 在
Potato Head.
蛋头
Potato Head?
Hey! Hey! Tuberous root-man! Wake up!
蛋头,给我起来
Impossible!
不可能
Hey!
嘿
Little late for a stroll, eh, Potato Head?
现在散步也太晚了点吧,蛋头
That's Mr. Potato Head to you, smoothie.
叫我蛋头先生,你这个小人
Well, well, well. You're turning out to be quite the troublemaker, aren't you?
你就是爱惹麻烦是吧
What did you think you were gonna do? Waltz right out of here?
你想怎么地,想跑吗
Yeah, and I would 've got away with it, too,
没错,要不是你的手下捣乱
if it weren't for you meddling toys!
其实我本都能跑掉了
You ascot- wearing pink- noser!
你这好管闲事的娘娘腔
You're not a toy! You're an accessory!
你根本不是玩具,你只不过是附属物罢了
You're a purse with legs.
毫无用处的家伙
Take him back to the box.
把他关进沙箱里去
No! No, not the box! I 'm sorry. I didn't mean it!
不,我不要去沙箱里,抱歉,我不是那个意思,
I like ascots.
我其实挺喜欢娘娘腔来着
Really. No, no, no!
不,别这样
Okay, check.
好,搞定
Good work, Lightyear. All right, resume your space-guy-thingy.
巴斯,干得不错,好了,继续当你那什么宇宙英雄去吧
Yes, sir, well-@groomed man!
遵命,仪表堂堂的长官
Ken! Ken?
肯,肯
What do you want?
你要干吗
I can't take it here, Ken. I wanna go to the Butterfly Room. With you!
肯,我受不了了,我想去蝴蝶屋,和你在一起
Yeah, well, you should 've thought of that yesterday.
你昨天就应该意识到的
I was wrong.
我错了
I wanna be with you, Ken, I do. In your Dream House.
我真的想和你一起待在你那梦幻小屋里
Please take me away from this! Take me away!
带我离开这儿好吗,带我走
Darn it, Barbie!
芭比,见鬼
Okay, but things are complicated around here.
好吧,但这里事情很复杂
- You gotta do what I say. - I will, Ken! I promise!
- 你必须要照我说的做 - 我会听你的,我保证
Wait. I 'll do anything! I 'll change your diapers!
等等,我愿意做任何事情,帮你换尿布也行啊
Go get the tape!
去,拿,胶,带
And this is where the magic happens.
这里就是奇迹发生的地方
Look at all your clothes!
看看这些衣服
I can't believe you never brought me up here!
我不敢相信你之前居然没带我来过
- Tennis whites? Mission to Mars! - I know, I know, I know.
- 白色网球套装,火星计划 - 我知道
Check this out! Kung fu fighting.
瞧瞧这个,功夫服
Campus hero with matching sports pennant, huh?
帆布英雄和与之配套的优胜锦旗
Flower power! Oh, Ken!
印花衫,天啊,肯
No one appreciates clothes here, Barbie. No one.
芭比,这里没人懂得欣赏服装,没有一人
Ken, would you model a few outfits for me?
肯,你能穿上几套炫给我看看吗
Just a few?
几套就好了
Go get the key.
去拿钥匙
Where is it, where is it?
在哪儿在哪儿,钥匙在哪儿
Where's the key? Where's the key? Bingo!
钥匙到底在哪儿,找到了
Hey! What do you think you're doing?
你以为你在干吗
I told you, keep your hands off of my stuff!
我早就和你说过,不许碰我的东西
Make a move, porky!
动手啊,你这肥猪
Hey, hey, hey! No fighting! Break it up!
不许打架,都给我住手
- Hey! Hey! - Take that, walnut-brain.
- 嘿 - 接住,榆木脑袋
No wonder you're extinct.
难怪你都要绝种了
Hey, you can't hit each other. That's my job!
你们不能打人,只有我可以
Help! Prison riot!
请求支援,监狱暴动
Get the tortilla.
去拿玉米薄饼
- Ready? - Ready.
- 准备好了吗 - 好了
Barbie?
芭比,你在哪儿
No more games, Ken! What did Lotso do to Buzz?
游戏结束,肯,罗梭到底对巴斯干了什么
And how do we switch him back?
我们怎么能将他回复原状
You can't make me talk. You can't!
我什么也不会说的,你拿我没办法
But I 'd like to see you try.
不信你试试看
Let's see. Hawaiian surf trunks.
让我看看,夏威夷冲浪短裤
Barbie! Those were vintage!
芭比,那可是古董衣
It's okay. All right, go ahead, rip 'em, I don't care.
没关系,你撕吧,我不在乎
They're a dime a dozen.
他们一点都不值钱
Glitter tux.
闪光礼服
Who cares? Who cares? Sequins are tacky. Who cares?
谁在乎,没人在乎,那些衣服太低俗了
A Nehru jacket.
尼赫鲁上装
Barbie! Not the Nehru.
芭比,不要撕尼赫鲁装啊
This is from what, 1967?
这是什么年代来着,1967年吧
The groovy formal collection, yes!
没错,最时髦的正装收藏
- What a shame. - Oh, no, no, no! No!
- 真可惜啊 - 不要,不要啊
There's an instruction manual!
有本使用说明书
Lotso switched Buzz to Demo mode!
罗梭把巴斯调到演示模式了
Where's that manual?
说明书在哪儿
I don't know why this couldn't wait until morning, Ken,
我真不懂为什么你不能等到早上,肯
but here you go.
不过拿去吧
What's takin' so doggone long?
搞什么鬼,怎么这么久
So how do we fix Buzz?
我们怎么才能修好巴斯
What are you looking at, feathers?
小鸟,你盯着我看干吗
Hey!
嘿
Yeah, fly away, you coward.
快飞走吧,胆小鬼
Well, that's just great.
真是棒极了
Help! Prison riot!
请求支援,监狱暴动
- Mayday! Mayday! - Give it up. No one can hear you.
- 请求帮助 - 别喊了,没人听得见
- What? - I said, "No one can hear you."
- 你说什么 - 我说没人听得见你
- What? - He said, "No one can..."
- 什么 - 他说,没人
Shush! Will you be quiet?
安静
Woody! You're back!
伍迪,你回来了
Stop him! Don't let him get out!
抓住他,别让他跑了
Star Command! I 've been taken hostage by my own prisoners.
星球总部,我被我所看守的犯人留作人质
Quick! Open his back. There's a switch!
快点,打开后盖,那儿有个开关
Unhand me, Zurg scum!
放开我,你们这些索戈人渣
The Galactic Courts will show you no mercy.
银河法院不会对你们仁慈的
It's not working. Why is it not working? Where's the manual?
不行,为什么不行,说明书在哪儿
Here we go! There should be a little hole under the switch.
在这儿,开关的下面应该有个小洞
- Little hole, got it! - "To reset your Buzz Lightyear,
- 小洞,找到了 - 如果要把巴斯光年恢复出厂设置
- "insert paperclip..." - Rex, use your finger!
- 插入回形针 - 雷克斯,用你的手指
What?
什么
- Okay, now what? - All right, let's see.
- 好了,现在怎么办 - 让我看看
"Caution. Do not hold button for more than five seconds."
注意别超过五秒
It's not my fault!
这不能怪我
[外语] 星球日志
[外语] 我在一个奇怪的行星上从深睡眠醒来
- Now what did you do? - I just did what you told me!
- 你到底干了什么 - 我只是照你说的做了
[外语] 我被未知生物包围
[外语] 谁在那儿
[外语] 是敌是友
Amigos! We're all amigos.
朋友,都是朋友
[外语] 我的飞船一定坠毁了,我的记忆也被消除了
[外语] 有人见到我的飞船了吗
We gotta switch him back.
我们得把他调回来
- Well, how do we do that? - I don't know. That part's in Spanish.
- 怎么调 - 不知道,这部分是西班牙语
We don't have time for this. Come on, El Buzzo.
我们没时间了,走吧,巴斯
[外语] 你知道我飞船在哪儿
[外语] 太好了
Good luck, cowboy.
牛仔,祝你好运
Here they come.
他们来了
Come on, Buzz!
巴斯,快过来
What took you so long?
怎么那么久
- Things got complicated. - Where's Potato Head?
- 情况变复杂了 - 蛋头在哪儿
We haven't seen him.
我们没见到他
Buzz.
巴斯
[外语] 我的沙漠之花
[外语] 我终于见到我的梦中情人
Did you fix Buzz?
你们把巴斯修好了吗
- Sort of. - Behind you.
- 差不多吧 - 你后面
Someone's coming.
有人在靠近
You would not believe what I 've been through tonight.
你们不会相信我今晚都经历了什么
Darling! Are you okay?
亲爱的,你还好吗
I feel fresh. Healthy. It's terrible.
我感觉很健康,焕然一新,其实糟糕极了
You've lost weight. And so tall.
你减肥了,还长高了
You're a sight for detachable eyes.
我还是喜欢这个样子多点
All clear.
一切正常
Come on. Come on.
过来,快点过来
We're almost there.
我们胜利在望了
Back up. Back up!
回去,快回去
Come on.
过来这边
[外语] 过来这边
[外语] 小姐,跟我来,我会带你去欣赏银河奇观
[外语] 而我们将在一起战胜恶魔
Woody!
伍迪
Come on. We're almost there.
快点,我们马上就到了
[外语] 可恶的牛仔
Buzz, come here. Give me a lift.
巴斯,过来帮我上去
[外语] 巴斯光年,拯救世界
[外语] 任务完成
Way to go, Buzz. Come on.
帅呆了,巴斯,走吧
- Is it safe? - I guess I 'll find out.
- 这安全吗 - 我去探探路
- Woody? You okay? - Yeah.
- 伍迪,你还好吧 - 我没事
Come on down. But not all at once.
下来吧,但不要一起下来
- What did he say? - I think he said, "All at once."
- 他说什么 - 我想他是叫我们一起下去
No. No. No, no, no, no, no!
不,不不
- Geronimo! - Look out!
- 啊呀 - 小心
Thanks, Jess.
洁西,谢了
[外语] 我的飞船在哪儿
Almost there, guys.
胜利就在眼前
Slink, you think you can make it?
弹簧狗,你能跳过去吗
Well, I might be old, but I still got a spring in my step.
我也许已经老了,但我仍然步伐矫健
- He did it! - All right, Slinkykins.
- 他成功了 - 弹簧狗,好样的
Okay, climb across.
好了,爬过来吧
You lost, little doggie?
小狗狗,迷路了吗
Well, well. Look who's back.
看看谁回来了
I'm sorry, cowboy.
牛仔,我很抱歉
They broke me.
他们废了我
What are y'all doing? Running back to your kid?
你们想干吗,跑回你们主人那儿吗
He don't want you no more.
他根本不要你们了
- That's a lie. - Is it?
- 骗人 - 是吗
Tell me this, Sheriff.
告诉我,警长
If your kid loves you so much, why is he leaving?
如果你的主人这么爱你,为什么他要走呢
You think you're special, cowboy?
牛仔,你别以为自己很特别
You're a piece of plastic. You were made to be thrown away.
你不过是块塑料罢了,你注定是要被丢弃的
Speak of the devil.
说曹操,曹操到
Now, we need toys in our Caterpillar Room
我们需要有玩具在毛毛虫屋
and you need to avoid that truck.
你们也不想被垃圾车装走
Why don't you come on back, join our family again?
浪子回头,重新加入我们的大家庭吧
This isn't a family! It's a prison! You're a liar and a bully!
这才不是什么大家庭,这里是监狱,你是个骗子和恶棍
And I 'd rather rot in this dumpster than join any family of yours!
我宁愿烂在这垃圾箱里也不要加入你的大家庭
Jessie's right! Authority should derive from the consent of the governed,
洁西说得没错,权力是由人民的同意授予
not from the threat of force.
而不是武力威胁得到
If that's what you want.
那就别怪我不客气了
Barbie! Wait! Don't do this, Lotso.
芭比,等等,罗梭,别这样
She's a Barbie doll, Ken. There's a hundred million just like her.
她不过是个芭比娃娃,世界上一抓一大把
Not to me, there's not.
对我来说她却是唯一的
Fine. Then why don't you join her!
好啊,那你也去他们那边吧
Oh, Ken!
肯
Everyone, listen!
大家都听我说
Sunnyside could be cool and groovy if we treated each other fair.
如果我们公平友好相处,阳光幼儿园会是个温馨的地方
It's Lotso. He's made us into a pyramid,
是罗梭建立的金字塔制度
and he put himself on top!
把自己放在顶端
Anyone concur with Ken?
有人赞成肯说的话吗
I didn't throw you away. Your kid did.
我可没把你们丢弃,是你们的主人把你们丢弃的
Ain't one kid ever loved a toy, really.
有孩子真正爱过一个玩具吗
Chew on that when you're at the dump.
在垃圾场里好好想想吧
Wait! What about Daisy?
等等,那黛西呢
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
Daisy? You used to do everything with her?
黛西,你曾经和她形影不离
- Yeah? Then she threw us out. - No.
- 没错,但她把我们丢弃了 - 不
- She lost you. - She replaced us!
- 她只是丢失了你们 - 她找新玩具替代了我们
She replaced you.
她替代了你
And if you couldn't have her then no one could.
要是你不能拥有她,那就没人可以
You lied to Big Baby and you've been lying ever since.
你骗了大宝宝,而且你一直在撒谎
- Where'd you get that? - She loved you, Lotso.
- 你哪儿弄来的, - 她曾经深爱着你,罗梭
She never loved me.
她从来没有爱过我
As much as any kid ever loved a toy.
一个孩子能有多爱玩具,她就有多爱你
Mama.
妈妈
What? You want your mommy back?
怎么了,想妈妈了吗
She never loved you. Don't be such a baby!
她从来没有爱过你,别这么孩子气了
Push 'em in. All of 'em!
把他们都推下去,全部都推下去
This is what happens when you dummies try to think.
这就是你们胡思乱想的后果
We're all just trash, waiting to be thrown away! That's all a toy is!
我们全是垃圾,等着被丢弃,玩具的命运就是如此
Hey, stop it! Put me down, you idiot!
快停下,你个白痴,把我放下来
No! No! Wait a minute! Big Baby, wait!
不,等等,大宝宝,等等
- He's gone! - Holy cow.
- 他完蛋了 - 天啊
Come on. Hurry!
快点过来啊
For crying out loud!
怎么会这样
[外语] 牛仔,快点
Woody!
伍迪
Oh, boy. Incoming!
天啊,车来了
Come on!
跳
Barbie, no!
芭比,别去
Woody!
伍迪
No!
不
Can you hear me? Is everyone okay?
能听到我说话吗,大家都没事吧
Of course not, you imbecile. We're doomed!
你个笨蛋,当然有事,我们死定了
Everyone, go to Buzz. Come on.
大家都去巴斯那里,速度
We all here? Slinky? Rex?
所有人都在吧,弹簧狗,雷克斯
Against the wall, everybody. Quick!
全部人靠边站,速度
[外语] 小姐,你在哪儿
Buzz!
巴斯
They'll never make it!
他们过不来了
Look out!
小心
Buzz!
巴斯
- Anyone see him? - Over here, y'all. I found him.
- 看到他了吗 - 我找到他了,在这儿呢
Buzz, you okay?
巴斯,你没事吧
Buzz! Buzz!
巴斯,巴斯
That wasn't me, was it?
那不是我身上的味道吧
Buzz, you're back! You're back, you're back, you're back, you're back!
巴斯,你回来了回来了回来了
Yes, I 'm back. Where have I been?
对,我回来了,我之前去哪儿了
Beyond infinity, Space Ranger.
飞向宇宙,太空游侠
Woody! So where are we now?
伍迪,我们现在在哪儿
In a garbage truck on the way to the dump!
在去垃圾场的垃圾车上
(垃圾场)
Hold on, we're going in!
抓紧,我们要下去了
You got all your pieces?
你零部件都在吧
The claw!
利爪
- My babies! - Hey, guys! No! No!
- 我的孩子们 - 伙计们,别过去
No!
不
Hang on!
坚持住
Woody! What do we do?
伍迪,我们怎么办
We'll be okay if we stay togeth...
我们只要在一起就不会有事
- Woody! - Slinky!
- 伍迪 - 弹簧狗
It's a magnet! Watch out!
是磁铁,小心
Don't worry, Slink, we'll get you down.
弹簧狗,别担心,我们会把你弄下来的
You might wanna take a look at this.
你先看看这个再说
Quick! Grab something metal!
快,抓点金属的东西
You heard the guy.
快按巴斯说的做
It's not working!
没用
Help! Help me. I 'm stuck!
救命,救我啊,我被卡住了
Help, please! Help!
救命啊
Woody!
伍迪
- Thank you. - Don't thank me yet.
- 谢了 - 先别谢我
Woody!
伍迪
Go, go!
快点,快点
Thank you, Sheriff.
警长,谢了
We're all in this together.
我们是一根绳上的蚂蚱
Right, guys?
大家说呢
Guys?
人呢
Woody! Down here!
伍迪,我们在这里
- Woody! - Oh, boy.
- 伍迪 - 伙计
Woody, look. I can see daylight.
伍迪,我能看见阳光了
We're gonna be okay!
我们会没事的
Hey!
嘿
I don't think that's daylight.
我不认为那是阳光
Run!
快跑
(停止按钮)
Sheriff! The button! Help me!
警长,那个按钮,帮我一把
Come on!
快点啊
Go. Go! Hit the button!
快去按按钮
Hurry!
快点
- Just push it! Push it! - Push it!
- 按啊,快按按钮 - 按啊
Where's your kid now, Sheriff?
警长,你的主人现在在哪儿呢
No. No!
不,不
Lotso!
罗梭
No!
不
Rex!
雷克斯
Buzz! What do we do?
巴斯,我们怎么办
The claw.
利爪
You know all that bad stuff I said about Andy's attic?
我之前说过的所有对阁楼的怨言
I take it all back.
我全部收回
- You're darn tootin'. - You said it.
- 你说得一点没错 - 你说出了我们的心声
Oh, darling. You were so brave.
亲爱的,你真勇敢
- You saved our lives. - And we are eternally grateful.
- 你救了我们 - 我们永远感谢你们
My boys!
我的孩子们
Daddy!
爸爸
Hey! Where's that fur ball Lotso?
那只毛茸茸的罗梭呢
Yeah. I 'd like to loosen his stitchin'.
我真想把他碎尸万段
Forget it, guys. He's not worth it.
算了吧,别跟他一般见识
- Hey! - What you got?
- 嘿 - 找到了什么好东东
I had me one of these when I was a kid.
我小时候玩过这个玩具
Strawberries.
草莓味的
Hey, buddy. You might wanna keep your mouth shut.
兄弟,你最好把嘴巴闭起来
Come on, Woody. We gotta get you home.
来吧,伍迪,我们要把你送回家
- That's right, college boy. - Wait.
- 没错,大学生 - 等等
What about you guys? I mean,
那你们怎么办
maybe the attic's not such a great idea.
也许阁楼并不是什么好主意
- We're Andy's toys, Woody. - We'll be there for him, together.
- 伍迪,我们是安迪的玩具 - 我们会一起在那儿等他的
- I just hope he hasn't left yet. - Wait a minute!
- 但愿他还没走 - 等等
Wait, I 'll check!
等等,我帮你看看
Andy's still packing. But he's almost done!
安迪还在收拾,不过已经快弄好了
- He lives halfway across town. - We'll never get there in time!
- 但他住在城市的另一边 - 我们永远也赶不上的
- Come on, Buster. - Is that it, honey? You got everything?
- 过来,巴斯特 - 亲爱的,都收拾好了吗
Yeah. Just a few more boxes in my room.
就差我房间里面的几个盒子
Okay. Come on.
好了,快点
That's enough. That's enough. That's enough!
够了
All right. Go. Go, go!
好了,快跑
Okay. All clear.
好了,安全
There you are.
你在这儿呢
- There you go. - Buzz.
- 进去了 - 巴斯
- This isn't goodbye. - Hey, Woody. Have fun at college.
- 这不是永别 - 伍迪,在大学玩得开心点
Yeah, but not too much fun.
没错,但别疯过头了
- Woody, take care of Andy. - Yeah.
- 伍迪,照顾好安迪, - 对呀
He's a good kid. Tell him to get a haircut.
他是个好孩子,叫他去理个发
Sure thing.
好的
Jessie, you'll be okay in the attic?
洁西,你在阁楼没问题吧
'Course I will. Besides, I know about
那当然,再说了,我知道
- Buzz's Spanish mode. - My what?
- 巴斯的西班牙模式了 - 我的什么
Honey, you want some food for the road?
亲爱的,路上带点吃的不
I 'll get something on the way.
我饿了路上买吧
You know where to find us, cowboy.
你知道在哪里可以找到我们,牛仔
Did you say goodbye to Molly?
你和莫莉说再见了吗
Mom, we've said goodbye like 10 times.
妈,我和她都道别十次了
Andy.
安迪
Mom, it's okay.
妈,没事的
I know. It's just...
我知道,我只是,
I wish I could always be with you.
真希望永远陪在你身边
You will be, Mom.
你会的,妈妈
Hey, aren't you gonna say goodbye to Buster?
你不和巴斯特说声再见吗
Of course I am. Who's a good doggy?
我当然会啦,谁是我的好狗狗
Who's a good doggy? I 'm gonna miss you. I 'm gonna miss you.
谁是我的好狗狗,我会想你,我会想你的
- I 'm gonna miss you. - Don't, Andy.
- 我会想你的 - 别了,安迪
Good boy. He's telling you to go already.
乖,他提醒你该出发了
Come on. Get the rest of your things.
把剩下的东西都收好吧
Okay, Buster. Now don't let Molly near my stuff.
再见了,巴斯特,别让莫莉动我的东西
Hey.
嘿
Hey, Mom! So, you really think I should donate these?
妈妈,你真的认为我应该把这些捐了吗
It's up to you, honey. Whatever you wanna do.
随你吧,亲爱的,你说了算
"Don't go in there! The bakery is haunted!"
别进去那里,糕饼店有鬼
"Are you crazy? You'll wake up all the ghosts."
你疯了吗,你会把鬼都吵醒的
"Look out! The ghosts are throwing pies!"
小心,鬼魂在向你扔派
Mom.
妈妈
- Andy? - Hi.
- 安迪 - 嗨
Wow. Look at you.
看看你
Well, I hear you're off to college.
我听说你要去上大学了
Yeah. Right now, actually.
没错,就要走了
So, what can we do for you?
我能帮到你什么吗
I have some toys here.
我这儿有些玩具
You hear that, Bonnie?
听到了吗,邦尼
So, you're Bonnie?
你就是邦尼吗
I 'm Andy.
我是安迪
Someone told me you're really good with toys.
有人告诉我你对玩具很好
These are mine, but I 'm going away now,
这些是我的玩具,但是我现在要离开了
so I need someone really special to play with them.
所以我希望能找一个很特别的人和他们一起玩
This is Jessie, the roughest, toughest cowgirl in the whole West.
这是洁西,整个西部最牛最厉害的牛仔女郎
She loves critters, but none more than her best pal, Bullseye.
她很喜欢《魔晶》,不过她更喜欢她最好的搭档,红心
Here.
给你
This is Rex, the meanest, most terrifying dinosaur who ever lived!
这是雷克斯,有史以来最坏最可怕的恐龙
The Potato Heads. Mr. And Mrs. You gotta keep 'em together,
这是蛋头先生和蛋头太太,你一定要把他们放在一起
'cause they're madly in love.
因为他们无比相爱
Now Slinky here is as loyal as any dog you could want.
这是弹簧狗,忠诚不二的狗狗
And Hamm, he'll keep your money safe,
还有火腿,保你钱财无失
but he's also one of the most dastardly villains of all time, evil Dr. Pork Chop.
但他同时也是世界上最怯懦的坏蛋,邪恶博士猪排
These little dudes are from a strange alien world.
这些小东西来自一个奇怪的世界
Pizza Planet.
披萨星球
And this
还有这个
is Buzz Lightyear, the coolest toy ever!
这是巴斯光年,史上最酷的玩具
Look, he can fly and shoot lasers!
你看,他可以飞,还能发射激光
He's sworn to protect the galaxy from the evil Emperor Zurg.
他发誓要保护宇宙免受邪恶索戈的控制
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇宙,浩瀚无限
Now, you gotta promise to take good care of these guys.
你得向我保证你会好好照顾这些家伙
They mean a lot to me.
他们对我来说无比重要
My cowboy!
我的牛仔
Woody? What's he doing in there?
伍迪,他在这里干吗
- "There's a snake in my boot." - Wha?
- 有只蛇在我的靴子里 - 什么
There's a snake in my boot.
有只蛇在我的靴子里
Now, Woody, he's been my pal for as long as I can remember.
从我记事开始,伍迪就是我的好伙伴了
He's brave, like a cowboy should be.
他很勇敢,就像真正的牛仔那样
And kind. And smart.
善良又聪明
But the thing that makes Woody special is he'll never give up on you.
但伍迪最特别的地方,就是他永远不会对你失去信心
Ever.
从不
He'll be there for you, no matter what.
不管发生了什么事情,他都会在你身边
You think you can take care of him for me?
你认为你可以帮我照顾好他吗
Okay then.
那好吧
Oh, no! Dr. Pork Chop's attacking the haunted bakery!
不好了,猪排博士在攻击闹鬼的糕饼店
The ghosts are getting away. Woody'll stop 'em!
鬼魂都在逃逸,伍迪会来阻止他们的
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
巴斯光年来拯救世界
And we'll actually need the rocket.
我们会需要这个火箭的
They're getting away! Come on, Bullseye!
他们要跑了,快
We need to get in the spaceship. The volcano is gonna erupt.
我们赶紧上飞船,火山要爆发了
Look! They're being attacked by a real dog!
看呀,有条狗在袭击他们
You can eat my poisonous scones!
来吧,尝尝这个毒饼
Mr. And Mrs. Potato Head are in trouble.
蛋头夫妇有麻烦了
Get on, Woody.
上车,伍迪
It's my friend Woody.
这是我的朋友伍迪
Buzz, hurry! Get your extra turbo booster.
巴斯,快,打开备用的涡轮增压
Thanks, guys.
谢谢你们,伙伴们
Look, Mommy. They're all playing together.
妈妈看,他们都在一起玩呢
Come on. Let's get some lunch.
过来吧,我们要吃午饭了
So long, partner.
再见了,伙伴
Hey, Buzz. You haven't met Bonnie's toys yet. Hey, come here.
巴斯,我来跟你介绍,这些是邦尼的玩具
You're gonna love them. Buzz, this is Dolly.
你会喜欢他们的,这位是多莉
New toys!
新玩具
Noses.
碰碰鼻子
"So I guess you could say Sunnyside is sunny once again!
现在阳光幼儿园终于重现阳光
"Hope to hear from you soon. We're all super excited about your new home.
希望很快再能收到你的消息,我们超级期待你的新家
"Hugs and kisses to everyone."
爱你们大家哦
That Barbie has some nice handwriting.
芭比字写得很好啊
Buzz, Barbie didn't write this.
巴斯,这不是芭比写的
- Grab the sword! - I got it!
- 拿着剑 - 拿好了
- Okay, go for the... - Triple bonus!
- 好,去赢得, - 三倍奖金
- Watch out! - We got the cloak of darkness!
- 小心 - 我们得到黑暗披风啦
- Run, run! - My arms are never long enough!
- 跑,快跑 - 我的手臂从不够长
I 'll do it! This is it! This is it!
我来,好了,好了
- Yes! - We did it!
- 帅 - 我们成功了
High-five! Hold on.
击掌,等等
Well, it's official. You guys made the wall.
你们正式上榜了
- Look at this! - Golly bob howdy! That's me!
- 看 - 神奇鲍勃,是我啊
We're all up here! Hey, Chuckles, lookin' good.
我们都在这了,看起来不错啊
Yeah, she really got your smile.
她真的能让你开心
What the...
怎么
I told you kids! Stay out of my butt!
告诉过你们了,孩子们,离我屁股远点
But soft, what light through yonder window breaks?
但那边窗缝里透出的是什么光
Romeo, o Romeo, wherefore art thou Romeo?
罗密欧啊,罗密欧,为什么罗密欧偏偏是你呢
Next season, we're doing Cats.
下一季,我们演《猫》
Or might I suggest Hamlet?
还是演《哈姆雷特》呢
Yeah. Detached wing. Cosmetic damage.
不管是只剩一只翅膀还是化妆掉了
Nothing a little duct tape can't fix.
大力胶都可以修复
I don't know what came over me.
我不知道自己是怎么了
Just go with it, Buzz.
跟着感觉走